<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike Treglia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mike Treglia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Going with Blogdown &amp; Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/20170123_blogdown_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20170123_blogdown_hugo/</guid>
      <description>Why Blogdown? As I&amp;rsquo;ve noted before, my previous website was pretty basic. While it was largely simple to make updates, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly elegant. It was functional, and definitely looked reasonable when it was first created. Editing it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult, but took some forethought if I wanted to make updates across the website. I&amp;rsquo;m not at all trained in web development, and just I picked up a few things by working off a template a friend created for me, and toying around with some .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for a Website Makeover</title>
      <link>/post/time-for-webpage-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time-for-webpage-update/</guid>
      <description>Time for a Change I got my original website started in the beginning of grad school (circa 2007), with great help from a college friend. As this one, it was static, but relied directly on CSS and HTML, with no real page generator in the sense of Jekyll or Hugo. It&amp;rsquo;s been great for me - serving as a place to link other projects I&amp;rsquo;ve developed; for example, a QGIS tutorial I wrote for a workshop, and materials from a GIS/Spatial Analysis course I taught as a postdoc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>A Bit About Me: I work as the Urban Spatial Planner for The Nature Conservancy&amp;rsquo;s New York City Program. In this role I use GIS, Remote Sensing, and statistical tools to characterize the current open space in the city, while thinking about how we can improve the state of biodiversity and develop resilience to climate change. I grew up in Staten Island, NY, and am delighted to now be working on conservation issues of my entire home city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code/</guid>
      <description>Overview iButton Data Organizer NetCDF Data Access LAStools Wrapper Functions from R
Overview I primarily use R for scientific computing, but also dabble in bash, and use SQL a fair bit for spatial stuff, working from PostgreSQL/PostGIS databases.
I&amp;rsquo;ll disclaim that I have limited formal training in coding, but have been really fortunate for opportunities to improve my skills through a few opportunities I&amp;rsquo;d encourage others to look into. First, in 2014 I attended a joint NCEAS/RENCI Open Science for Synthesis session, focused in training early career scientists useful computing tools to allow for reproducible research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>E-mail Work: michael.treglia(at)tnc.org  Personal: mtreglia(at)gmail.com
Mailing Address Michael Treglia  The Nature Conservancy  322 8th Ave, 16th Floor  New York, NY 10001</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/photography/</guid>
      <description> Content Coming Soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a list of my publicationsClick here for my complete CV
Current Work My current work is broadly focused on using statistical and and GIS tools to inform conservation efforts. Working for The Nature Conservancy in New York City, I using available remote sensing data and GIS datasets to characterize open space dynamics, understand how connected wildlife populations might be across the city, and map previously-unmapped assets, like green roofs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>QGIS Tutorial QGIS is a well-developed, open source GIS program, with a wide range of features and great compatability with numerous formats. Furthermore, basic installation includes linkages with other open source GIS tools such as GRASS GIS and SAGA (among others). It is one primary software packages that I use in research and teach in classes.
This tutorial is designed to familiarize GIS users with the general layout, features and tools of QGIS, through working with sample datasets that are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>