<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike Treglia</title>
    <link>https://mltconsecol.github.io</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mike Treglia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Michael L. Treglia.&lt;br&gt;All rights reserved.</copyright>
    
        <atom:link href="https://mltconsecol.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike Treglia, PhD</title>
      <link>https://mltconsecol.github.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mltconsecol.github.io/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my webpage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Mike Treglia and I work as the Lead Scientist for the Cities program with The Nature Conservancy in New York. In this role I use GIS, Remote Sensing, and statistical tools to characterize the current open space in the city, while thinking about how we can improve the state of biodiversity and develop resilience to climate change. In my work, I leverage vast amounts of open data, and am passionate about developing and sharing open source workflows as possible, in hopes that others will be able to build off of my efforts, without concern for licensing costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in Staten Island, NY, and am delighted and privileged to now be working on conservation issues of my entire home city. I am fortunate to have incredible collaborators and partners throughout my work, and incredible mentors throughout my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally try to maintain this website as a place for others to find occasional &lt;a href=&#34;post&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt;, to share a bit about my ongoing and past &lt;a href=&#34;research&#34;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;code&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;teaching&#34;&gt;teaching resources&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve developed through the years. I hope you find this useful! Feel free to reach out with questions or to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>